ILGWU Canadian Publications 5780/172
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Canadian Publications
1936-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/172
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Publications (documents).
This collection includes Canadian publications by and about the International Ladies' Garment Workers'
5512091
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
C. Berne, July 28, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/169: ILGWU Local Publications
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--Canada.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--Canada.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--Canada.; Industrial relations--United States.; Industrial relations--Canada.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5512091
- ILGWU Canada Pamphlets, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  In Italian and French
  - Item 1: L'UIOVD Siamo Noi, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Item is in Italian.
  - Item 2: L'U.I.O.V.D. C'est Nous, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Item is in French.
  - Item 3: Education Programme, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Item is in English; French.
  - Item 4: Dressmakers..., Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Local 262. Item is in English; French.
- Winnipeg Needle Trades Council Annual Journal, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Winnipeg Needle Trades Council Annual Journal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Needle Trades Council of Greater Winnipeg. New Year's Eve Ball and Frolic. Souvenir Journal. Item is in English.
- ILGWU Joint Council Cloak and Dressmakers Union Journal, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  January 18
  - Item 1: ILGWU Joint Council Cloak and Dressmakers Union Twenty-Fifth Jubilee, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    January 18, 1936. Souvenir Program. Item is in English.
- Memorandum on Behalf of the ILGWU Presented to the Royal Commission on Canadian Economic Prospects by Shane Bernard, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  February 21
  - Item 1: Memorandum on Behalf of the ILGWU Presented to the Royal Commission on Canadian Economic Prospects, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Shane Bernard. February 21, 1956. Item is in English.
- Toronto Cloakmakers Union 40th Anniversary Souvenir Journal, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Toronto Cloakmakers Union 40th Anniversary Souvenir Journal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    December 22, 1949. 2 copies. Item is in English; Yiddish.
- Montreal Dressmakers Union 15th Anniversary Journal, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  in English and French
  - Item 1: Montreal Dressmakers Union 15th Anniversary Journal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Local 262. 2 copies. Item is in English; French.
- Toronto Joint Board Cloakmakers Union 50th Anniversary Souvenir Journal, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Toronto Joint Board Cloakmakers Union 50th Anniversary Souvenir Journal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Item is in English; Yiddish.
- Montreal Dress Manufacturers' Guild Memorandum on Behalf of the Dress Industry Presented to the Royal Commission on Canada's Economic Prospects, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  January 13
  - Item 1: Montreal Dress Manufacturers' Guild Memorandum on Behalf of the Dress Industry Presented to the Royal Commission on Canada's Economic Prospects, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    January 13, 1956. Item is in English.
- Statement Before the Textile and Clothing Board - Testimony on Behalf of the ILGWU in Canada, by Stephen Perkal, 1980; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  February 13
  - Item 1: Statement Before the Textile and Clothing Board - Testimony on Behalf of the ILGWU in Canada, by Stephen Perkal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Stephen Perkal. February 13, 1980. Item is in English.
- Toronto Cloakmakers' Union 25th Anniversary Souvenir Journal, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Toronto Cloakmakers' Union 25th Anniversary Souvenir Journal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    February 14-16, 1936. Item is in English; Yiddish.